# Curriculum Vitae of Erhan Yaşar

Personal Information

Turkish 13.07.1985

+90 533 494 0 400 mail@erhanyasar.com.tr erhanyasar.com.tr Moda, Istanbul / Turkey



### **Desired Position**

# Frontend Architect

### Summary

After graduating as a Computer Engineer and a Navy Ensign upon completing Naval High School and Naval Academy respectively, I served 6.5 years on various assignments as a Turkish Navy Officer under command of NATO and UN as well. After studying master, I shifted my career into research, design, and development of UX & Frontend, whilst literally retiring from Army. Apart from being a full-time developer, I'm training a class of 15 people on Frontend Development. Besides being happy to be involved in any phases amongst product to IT infrastructure, I feel much more confident when I focus on architectural Frontend and cognitive experience behind it in regard to assure end-to-end service quality.

# Work Experience

- Bilişim Education Center	Sep 2021 - Mar 2022	Software Trainer
Jan 2020 - Current		Senior Frontend Developer
- Testimonial Tree (Remote)	Jun 2021 - Current	
- Intellectsoft (Remote)	Apr 2022 - July 2022	
- Devtagon	Aug 2020- Mar 2021	

Jul 2014 - Oct 2018

- Related Digital

- Intern Officer

- eSystems

| Oct 2017 - Oct 2018 | Jun 2016 - Jun 2017

- Arete Consulting- erhanyasar.com.tr

| Jul 2014 - Jun 2016

| Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

# Sep 2007 - Dec 2013

# North Task Group Command Headquarter's Officer TCG KEMALREIS (F-247) Anti-Submarine Warfare Officer TCG YILDIRIM (F-243) Underwater Weapons Officer Jun 2008 - Jul 2011

**Navy Officer @ Turkish Naval Forces** 

| Sep 2007 - Jun 2008

Frontend Developer

Education

2013 - 2020 Mimar Sinan Fine Arts University
2003 - 2007 Naval Academy
2003 - 2007 Naval Academy
MSc | Computational Art & Design
BEng | Computer Engineering
BSc | Naval Science

# Skills & Competences

- Turkish (Native), English (Advanced, IELTS 6.5 Overall Academic), French (Intermediate)
- Oceangoing Watchkeeping Officer / Yatch Captain / 2\* CMAS diver
- A/A1/A2/B/B1/D1/F/M class driver's license

# Appreciations & Publications

- Fleet C.O. & TCG YILDIRIM (F-243) C.O. Appreciations 3 times in total
- Measuring Cognitive Friction on Mobile E-Commerce Applications (Master thesis)

#### Terms & Conditions

- Full-time | Remote | Employed (Preferably)
- Visa required in case of relocation
- Depending on relocation area, expected salary is not under \$100K as net, annually

### References

- Efe Aras, Founder of Visilabs
- James Gilchrist, Engineering Director of Testimonial Tree
- Salih Ofluoğlu, Prof.Dr., Chief of Enformatics at Mimar Sinan Fine Arts University